Brian Elias Montellano - Software Engineer; (323) 714-8839

bmontellano@gmail.com; Playa Del Rey, CA
linkedin.com/in/brian-montellano-b62527135
github.com/bmontellano
bmontellano.github.io/Brian Elias Montellano

Summary

I'm a web developer. I currently work with HTML, CSS, JS frameworks+libraries and Ruby with Rails. I'm also working on Java/Android mobile development using IntelliJ IDEA. You can find my work and portfolio on Git + Github. Before developing, I tutored grade school math, science and worked as a laboratory chemist. From these experiences I gained analytical skills, use of complex machinery, troubleshooting by scanning my work for errors, and patience to understand material and deliver it comprehensively. I'm always learning and I'm always willing to collaborate and share what I know.

Skills

Computer Languages:

-HTML, CSS, Javascript

-Ruby

Frameworks, Libraries & Technologies:

- -Mongo DB, Express, React, Node.js, Ruby on Rails
- jQuery,Bootstrap, Sass, AJAX

Human Languages:

Bilingual in Spanish

Projects

- 1. HangBoat web-game using Javascript and jQuery for DOM manipulation.
- 2. <u>Cat2Nap</u> full-stack Ruby on Rails application using Amazon Web Services server. Cat-owners site where individuals can post pictures of their cats, for sitting or showing off purposes.
- 3. <u>RoadRadar</u> MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js (MEN stack) application. Crowd sourced reporting of traffic incidents using indicators that have min. ago time stamping, and use of Gmaps API.
- 4. <u>ChatrBoxx</u> Mongo, Express, Node application. Simple chat application, utilizing Socket.io websocket technology for live chatting and Giphy API to post random GIFs.

Work Experience

Tutor, Study Hut - Oct 2016 to March 2017 Manhattan Beach, CA

- Tutor High School Students in Chemistry, Biology, Physiology, and Mathematics.
- Act as a mentor/coach helping students to create pathways for attainment of higher education

Sales Engineer, American Elements, Merelex Corporation – Jan 2013 to Dec 2013 Los Angeles, CA

- Start-up company environment, manager of sales. Worked 20% remotely using Go to My PC access.
- Used Filemaker Pro as main database. Assisted clients in selection of advanced compounds.

Research Associate, Molecular Sciences Dept at UCLA- Sept 2011 to May 2012 Los Angeles, CA

- Miguel Garcia-Garibay organic chemistry group synthesizing molecular gyroscopes, stators and rotors.
- Utilized knowledge in organic chemistry and collaborated with associates on synthesis of novel compounds.
- Gathered and analyzed data using Nuclear Magnetic Resonance, Mass Spectrometry, and UV spectroscopy.

Research Assistant, Semel Institute for Neuroscience at UCLA – June 2009 to Sept 2009 Los Angeles, CA

- ADHD Research team: Data management using Excel, SAS, and handling human tissue samples.

Tutor, Citrus College - Sept 2006 to May 2008 Glendora, CA

- Tutor of Calculus, Algebra, Trigonometry, and General & Organic Chemistry.
- Received the Tutor of the year award for the 2007-2008 school year.

Education

University of California, Los Angeles - B.A. in Sociology, Pre-Med with applied chemical research, Fall 2011. *General Assembly, Santa Monica, CA* - Web Development Immersive, August 2017.